FRONT-END DEVELOPER Florian J. Giraud

Marseille, France (ready to relocate)

- **©** 06 25 60 69 28
- 💌 florianj.giraud@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/jiro-jasmin
- github.com/jiro-jasmin

Portfolio: jiro-jasmin.com

ABOUT ME

Passionate about new technologies, I decided to move into the challenging field of web development after an initial background in languages and two years spent in Tokyo studying and working. As a freelance web developer, I have acquired a solid expertise especially in **React**. I can adapt quickly and I like to take on new challenges every day. I am ready to bring my technical skills and my creative mind as a **front-end developer**, in order to contribute to the growth of an ambitious startup.



TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML & CSS	JavaScript	PHP	Design
Sass	TypeScript	Symfony	Figma, Balsamio
PostCSS	React, Next.js	Kirby CMS	Material Design
BEM	Strapi CMS	Wordpress	
Bootstrap	API & JSON	SQL	Work tools
Tailwind	jQuery	Merise method	Trello, Kanban
	Webpack	Object Oriented	Git & Github

SOFT SKILLS

I completed the following MOOCs on OpenClassrooms.com:

- Project Management
- Agile and scrum methodologies
- <u>Drafting of functional specification</u>
- Creativity and Design Thinking

EDUCATION

Web developer training program

11/2021 – 10/2022 Afpa Digital Territory

Front-end skills:

- Web app mock-ups
- Mobile-first responsive, static & dynamic UI
- CMS customization

Back-end skills:

- Database implementation & management
- Access & interaction with data
- User authentication
- National RNCP certification of Web developer

BA Japanese studies & BA Anthropology

09/2014 - 06/2018 Aix-Marseille University

LANGUAGES

- > French (native)
- > English C1 level (fluent)
- > Japanese C1 level (fluent)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web developer @Freelance

Marseille (remote) | 10/2022 - today

Realisations:

- I added new functionalities in the back-office of <u>the website</u> I developed during my internship
- Re-design and SEO (meta tags, content drafting) here and there
- I am developing a new portfolio website with React, Next.js and the back-office with the headless CMS Strapi (work in progress)

Web developer @Edda Rabold

Germany (remote) | 06 - 09/2022

Internship: I designed and developed a creative online portfolio for a client from scratch, using MAMP stack and Kirby CMS.

- I designed mock-ups of the app using Figma
- I created animations and made the website dynamic
- I made the website fully responsive and SEO-friendly
- I used a CMS to make the content customizable by the client
- I worked under an agile methodology, using Trello's Kanban for project management and regular meetings with the client
- Realisation: fabiolaamaudricduchaffaut.fr

Academic Support Helper @Association Socrate

Paris | 10/2020 - 06/2021

Volunteering: I coordinated and organized workshops in primary and middle schools in less priviledged areas. Soft skills: project management, intercultural communication, flexibility.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Blog realized with React, Next.js, SCSS & back-office with Strapi CMS: <u>Code</u> | <u>Video</u>
- Audio streaming app, realised with React, Next.js, TypeScript: <u>Live Demo | Code | Video</u>
- E-commerce with customized back-office, realised with Bootstrap, JavaScript, PHP, SQL: <u>Live Demo</u> | <u>Code</u> | <u>Video</u>
- My portfolio, a SEO-friendly landing page, realised with Tailwind, TypeScript, React, Next.js: <u>Live Demo</u> | <u>Code</u> | <u>Video</u>
- And dozen of other finished projects on my Github